<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Introduction on TMLHB</title><link>https://do2blehelix.github.io/the-ml-handbook/handbook/</link><description>Recent content in Introduction on TMLHB</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy;{year}, All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 06:14:22 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://do2blehelix.github.io/the-ml-handbook/handbook/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Statistics</title><link>https://do2blehelix.github.io/the-ml-handbook/handbook/statistics/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 06:14:22 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://do2blehelix.github.io/the-ml-handbook/handbook/statistics/</guid><description>Statistics Descriptive Statistics : Provides statistical information about whole sets of data or populations.
Inferential Statistics : Provides statistical information about a dataset represented by a sample. It does so through a sample of the same population.
Collected Data types Time Series : Data collected over a period of time. (eg: same guy at different age) Cross Sectional : Data collected at one point in time. (eg: different guys at one point in time) Pooled : Combination of cross sectional and Time series data.</description></item><item><title>Supervised Learning</title><link>https://do2blehelix.github.io/the-ml-handbook/handbook/supervised-learning/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 06:14:22 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://do2blehelix.github.io/the-ml-handbook/handbook/supervised-learning/</guid><description>Supervised Learning In Supervised Learning, you have labelled data and are trying to predict a label (dependent variable) based on known features (independent variables). Historical data predicts likely future events.
Supervised Learning applies already learned concepts from a training dataset to a test dataset.
Common Types Regression Classification Learners Weak : Model which explains the variance more or less accurately Strong : Model which explains the variance accurately</description></item><item><title>Reinforcement Learning</title><link>https://do2blehelix.github.io/the-ml-handbook/handbook/reinforcement-learning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://do2blehelix.github.io/the-ml-handbook/handbook/reinforcement-learning/</guid><description>Reinforcement Learning</description></item><item><title>NLP</title><link>https://do2blehelix.github.io/the-ml-handbook/handbook/nlp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://do2blehelix.github.io/the-ml-handbook/handbook/nlp/</guid><description>Natural Language Processing NLP can be divided in supervised and unsupervised techniques
Supervised: Text Classification (Spam Recognition, labeling, etc) Spam Detection Sentiment Analysis Intent Classification Multi-Label, Multi-Class Text Classification Unsupervised: Topic Modeling Applications
Sentiment Analysis Speech Recognition Chatbot Machine Translation (Google Translate) Spell Checking Keyword Search Information Extraction Advertisement Matching NLU - Natural Language Understanding Mapping input to useful representations Analyzing different aspects of the language NLG - Natural Language Generation Text planning Sentence planning Text realization Ambiguities Lexical Ambiguity - Two or more possible meanings in a word.</description></item><item><title>Unsupervised Learning</title><link>https://do2blehelix.github.io/the-ml-handbook/handbook/unsupervised-learning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://do2blehelix.github.io/the-ml-handbook/handbook/unsupervised-learning/</guid><description>Unsupervised Learning In Unsupervised Learning, you have non labelled data and are trying to group together similar data points based off of features. No concept of Dependent and Independent Variables
In Unsupervised Learning, the system is not told the ‘right answer’ and the algorithm figures out the relations or attributes.
Used for: Segmenting text topics Recommend items Identify data outliers</description></item></channel></rss>