<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Statistics on TMLHB</title><link>https://do2blehelix.github.io/the-ml-handbook/handbook/statistics/</link><description>Recent content in Statistics on TMLHB</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy;{year}, All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 06:14:22 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://do2blehelix.github.io/the-ml-handbook/handbook/statistics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Central Tendency</title><link>https://do2blehelix.github.io/the-ml-handbook/handbook/statistics/1-central-tendency/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:38:25 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://do2blehelix.github.io/the-ml-handbook/handbook/statistics/1-central-tendency/</guid><description>Measures of Central Tendency Central tendency refers to the definition of a distribution of numbers by a particular central number. Generally speaking, it&amp;rsquo;s the most common number or most probable common number among a range of numbers.
If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever used the word &amp;lsquo;average&amp;rsquo; in a sentence, eg On an average the temperature is 25 degrees here, you are more than familiar with the concept already.
Mean, Median and Mode are are the top 3 measures of central tendency.</description></item><item><title>Dispersion/Spread</title><link>https://do2blehelix.github.io/the-ml-handbook/handbook/statistics/2-dispersion-spread/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:38:25 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://do2blehelix.github.io/the-ml-handbook/handbook/statistics/2-dispersion-spread/</guid><description>Measures of Dispersion/Spread While central tendency represents a range of numbers with a single value (except in some cases), the measures of dispersion shows us how evenly the data are spread.
Standard Deviation (σ) Standard Deviation, put simply shows how much the data deviates from the mean. It represents how far the data are dispersed from the mean. How much the members of a group differ from the mean value for the group.</description></item><item><title>Distributions</title><link>https://do2blehelix.github.io/the-ml-handbook/handbook/statistics/3-distributions/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:38:25 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://do2blehelix.github.io/the-ml-handbook/handbook/statistics/3-distributions/</guid><description>Distributions Now that we&amp;rsquo;ve seen the central point of a distribution, and then the deviation of data from the central point, let&amp;rsquo;s explore how these distributions look like.
Before we explore the distributions, its necessary to understand a few key terminologies
Skewness Skewness is the lack of symmetry of a distribution
Positive skewed = data is heavy towards the left ; tail towards the right Negative skewed = data is heavier towards the right ; tail towards the left Kurtosis Kurtosis simply refers to the pointiness of the curve.</description></item><item><title>Covariance &amp; Correlation</title><link>https://do2blehelix.github.io/the-ml-handbook/handbook/statistics/4-covariance-correlation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:38:25 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://do2blehelix.github.io/the-ml-handbook/handbook/statistics/4-covariance-correlation/</guid><description>Covariance &amp;amp; Correlation Correlation is a statistical technique that can show whether and how strongly pairs of variables are related. For example, height and weight are related; taller people tend to be heavier than shorter people.
⚠️ Correlation doesn&amp;rsquo;t imply causation
Covariance : Covariance is nothing but a measure of correlation. On the contrary, correlation refers to the scaled form of covariance.
Returns a value between -∞ &amp;amp; +∞
Sum [(X-u1) (Y-u2)] / (n-1)</description></item><item><title>Hypothesis Testing</title><link>https://do2blehelix.github.io/the-ml-handbook/handbook/statistics/5-hypothesis-testing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:38:25 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://do2blehelix.github.io/the-ml-handbook/handbook/statistics/5-hypothesis-testing/</guid><description>Hypothesis Testing It the the action of declaring a hypothesis (a fundamental logical component) and proving its occurrence of proving its non-existence.
Types of Hypothesis Null Hypothesis H0 : μ1 = μ2x
The means of the two groups (μ1 &amp;amp; μ2) belong to the same population. (p &amp;gt; 0.05)
Alternative Hypothesis HA : μ1 ≠ μ2
The means of the two groups (μ1 &amp;amp; μ2) belong to different populations.</description></item><item><title>Statistical Tests</title><link>https://do2blehelix.github.io/the-ml-handbook/handbook/statistics/6-statistical-tests/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://do2blehelix.github.io/the-ml-handbook/handbook/statistics/6-statistical-tests/</guid><description>Statistical Tests Statistical tests are conducted to accept or reject hypothesis. They can be divided into tests catering to specific distributions of data.
Parametric Test : used for normally distributed data (assess group means) Non-Parametric Test : used for skewed data (assess group medians) The tests are also classified according to their tails.
One Tailed : uni-directional (typing speed increases with more typing) Two tailed: bi-directional (typing speed can increase or decrease with more typing) ⚠ P-value is the probability of the sample means coming up equal to or even further away from the hypothesized population mean.</description></item></channel></rss>